title,link,keywords,creator,video_url,description,content,pubDate,full_description,image_url,source_id,is_healthcare,entities
What the U.S. can — and cannot — do for vaccine equity per the State Department,https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2021/10/25/1048969043/what-the-u-s-can-and-cannot-do-for-vaccine-equity-per-the-state-department,,['NPR Staff'],,The U.S. has pledged to deliver 1.1 billion doses of COVID vaccines to countries in need. Billions more are needed. NPR interviewed the State Department's global vaccine coordinator to learn more.,The U.S. has pledged to deliver 1.1 billion doses of COVID vaccines to countries in need. Billions more are needed. NPR interviewed the State Department's global vaccine coordinator to learn more.(Image credit: Leonardo Munoz/AFP via Getty Images),2021-10-25 22:18:02,,,npr,True,"[('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('1.1 billion', 'CARDINAL'), ('COVID', 'ORG'), ('Billions', 'CARDINAL'), ('NPR', 'ORG'), (""the State Department's"", 'ORG'), ('Leonardo Munoz/AFP', 'PERSON'), ('Getty Images', 'ORG')]"
"Heart to Heart raises $750K to bring sweet, sweet flirtation to your ear-holes",https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/heart-to-heart-dating-pre-seed/,"['Funding', 'Health', 'Media', 'Mobile', 'Recent Funding', 'Startups', 'oatv', 'precursor ventures', 'The Shade Room']",['Haje Jan Kamps'],,"Radio has long been described as the most intimate of media. Quips about putting radio on the internet aside, the persistent popularity of podcasting and the cockamamie climb of Clubhouse shows that audio-based platforms will continue to echo around the upper echelons of the ecosystem for a while yet. Joining the fray is Heart to […]","Radio has long been described as the most intimate of media. Quips about putting radio on the internet aside, the persistent popularity of podcasting and the cockamamie climb of Clubhouse shows that audio-based platforms will continue to echo around the upper echelons of the ecosystem for a while yet. Joining the fray is Heart to Heart, an audio-first dating app aiming to bring back some intimacy to the process of finding the right person for your next foray, whether that’s a saucy encounter or a mate for life. “I used to act, and from my time in acting, I saw how much voice, and audio experiences drive intimacy between people,” explains Joshua Ogundu, co-founder and CEO of Heart to Heart. “When it came down to the dating apps, it was never something I could get into. I felt like you needed to come up with a textual one-liner. That was never my way of approaching romantic conversations.” Heart to Heart is pushing back against the endless swiping and messaging of many of its competitors, offering a contrasting experience to sending the same opening line to dozens of people or typing with your thumbs until deep into the night. “I believe that the best consumer investments come from people who have unique insights on consumer behavior and ways that new tech products can allow new forms of social interaction,” said Charles Hudson from Precursor Ventures, who led the pre-seed investment round. “I have been a big fan of Josh’s TikTok videos for some time and his ability to poke at the tech industry with timely, relevant videos really showcased his creativity and ability to communicate via short-form video. I think the idea around confirming photos, storytelling, and audio will yield a product that really speaks to people’s unmet needs around communication and will create a whole new way for people to connect.” While Precursor doesn’t particularly focus on audio-first startups, the team has seen a number of opportunities in that space. It was an early investor in Howard Akumiah’s company, Betty Labs (acquired by Spotify), as well as Isa Watson’s company (Squad), Falon Fatemi’s company (Fireside) and several others that are still in stealth. “I believe that there is a major wave of interesting activity happening around non-music audio and I believe that we are still in the early innings of non-music, audio-driven social experiences,” says Hudson. “The last two companies that I feel really innovated in this category were Tinder and Bumble. I think Josh and his team have a new mechanic that feels differentiated and unique and I think it has the potential to be the foundation for a new way for people to meet and get to know each other in ways that aren’t easily accomplished today.” Joshua Ogundu, co-founder and CEO of Heart to Heart (Photo provided by Heart to Heart) The company raised the pre-seed round of $750,000. The round was led by Precursor Ventures, and Bryce Roberts of OATV & Angelica Nwandu of The Shade Room partnered on the investment, as well as Marie Rocha at Realist Ventures. In addition, a number of angel investors joined the round, including Chris Bennett (Wonderschool), Andy Weissman (USV) and Gregory Levey (Robinson Huntly). “The main thing we are trying to accomplish with the $750K, is to focus on building our iOS app, and making LA our first launch market,” says Ogundu. “Dating is such a local experience, and it makes sense to us to build and improve locally, then scaling it up from there.” “Voice is so intentional and intimate, and that is exactly what we’re building here at Heart to Heart,” says Ogundu, suggesting that the voice mechanic is helpful in a dating context because it helps slow people down. “I think that because it takes more energy to send that voice snippet to someone, you’ll be more intentional with who you even look to strike up conversations with.” The founding team consists of Joshua Ogundu, who wears the CEO hat. He is joined by Arihant Jain and Komal Shrivastava, who have been heading up the engineering and design efforts. The company hopes to get its product to market by the end of the year.",2021-10-25 18:30:46,,,techcrunch,True,"[('Radio', 'ORG'), ('Clubhouse', 'ORG'), ('Joshua Ogundu', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('dozens', 'CARDINAL'), ('the night', 'TIME'), ('Charles Hudson', 'PERSON'), ('Precursor Ventures', 'ORG'), ('Josh’s', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Howard Akumiah’s', 'PERSON'), ('Betty Labs', 'PERSON'), ('Spotify', 'ORG'), ('Isa Watson’s', 'ORG'), ('Falon Fatemi’s', 'PERSON'), ('Hudson', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tinder and Bumble', 'ORG'), ('Josh', 'PERSON'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Joshua Ogundu', 'PERSON'), ('750,000', 'MONEY'), ('Precursor Ventures', 'ORG'), ('Bryce Roberts', 'PERSON'), ('OATV & Angelica Nwandu of The Shade Room', 'ORG'), ('Marie Rocha', 'PERSON'), ('Realist Ventures', 'ORG'), ('Chris Bennett', 'PERSON'), ('Andy Weissman', 'PERSON'), ('USV', 'ORG'), ('Gregory Levey', 'PERSON'), ('$750K', 'MONEY'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ogundu', 'PERSON'), ('Ogundu', 'PERSON'), ('Joshua Ogundu', 'PERSON'), ('Komal Shrivastava', 'PERSON'), ('the end of the year', 'DATE')]"
Moderna reports positive results for COVID-19 vaccine in younger children,https://healthwise.punchng.com/moderna-reports-positive-results-for-covid-19-vaccine-in-younger-children/,"['News', '#COVID-19 vaccine for children', '#Moderna COVID-19 vaccine']",['Agency'],,"United States biotech firm Moderna said on Monday that its COVID-19 vaccine was safe and produced a strong immune response in children aged 6-11, adding it would submit trial data to global regulators soon. The news comes as a panel of government advisors was preparing to meet Tuesday on the question of whether to authorize […] The post Moderna reports positive results for COVID-19 vaccine in younger children appeared first on Healthwise.","United States biotech firm Moderna said on Monday that its COVID-19 vaccine was safe and produced a strong immune response in children aged 6-11, adding it would submit trial data to global regulators soon. The news comes as a panel of government advisors was preparing to meet Tuesday on the question of whether to authorize the Pfizer vaccine in kids aged 5-11, with top infectious disease expert Anthony Fauci predicting it would be available by mid-November. “We are encouraged by the immunogenicity and safety profile of mRNA-1273 in children aged 6 to under 12 years and are pleased that the study met its primary immunogenicity endpoints,” Moderna chief executive Stephane Bancel said in a statement. An interim analysis from a mid-to-late stage clinical trial of 4,753 children showed that two doses of vaccine produced a high level of neutralizing antibodies – Y-shaped proteins that bind to the coronavirus and block it from entering human cells. The vaccine was dosed at 50 micrograms, which is half of what is used among adults, but still produced on average 1.5 times as many antibodies in children as it did in young adults given the higher dose. The majority of adverse events were mild or moderate, including fatigue, headache, fever, and injection site pain. These early results, released via a press statement, do not yet include a vaccine efficacy estimate, which may be expected at a later time once cases have accrued. – FDA meeting on Pfizer – The Moderna news comes as the US Food and Drug Administration is preparing to convene a panel of advisors to vote on whether to greenlight the Pfizer shot for younger children, paving the way for 28 million more Americans to be vaccinated. A briefing document posted on the FDA’s website indicated the agency believes benefits outweigh the most worrying side effect for this age group, namely myocarditis, or heart inflammation. “The overall analysis predicted that the numbers of clinically significant COVID-19-related outcomes prevented would clearly outweigh the numbers of vaccine-associated excess myocarditis cases,” the document said. But it acknowledged the benefit-risk calculus would differ when community transmission is very low, as was the case in the United States in June 2021. The FDA also uploaded Pfizer’s efficacy analysis, with the company estimating a two-dose course of its vaccine at 10 micrograms was more than 90 percent effective in preventing symptomatic disease. Overall, more than 150 children aged 5 to 11 have died from Covid in the United States since the start of the pandemic, according to official data. “If all goes well, and we get the regulatory approval and the recommendation from the CDC, it’s entirely possible, if not very likely, that vaccines will be available for children from 5 to 11 within the first week or two of November,” Fauci told ABC News Sunday. (AFP) The post Moderna reports positive results for COVID-19 vaccine in younger children appeared first on Healthwise.",2021-10-25 15:02:03,"United States biotech firm Moderna said on Monday that its COVID-19 vaccine was safe and produced a strong immune response in children aged 6-11, adding it would submit trial data to global regulators soon. The news comes as a panel of government advisors was preparing to meet Tuesday on the question of whether to authorize the Pfizer vaccine in kids aged 5-11, with top infectious disease expert Anthony Fauci predicting it would be available by mid-November. “We are encouraged by the immunogenicity and safety profile of mRNA-1273 in children aged 6 to under 12 years and are pleased that the study met its primary immunogenicity endpoints,” Moderna chief executive Stephane Bancel said in a statement. An interim analysis from a mid-to-late stage clinical trial of 4,753 children showed that two doses of vaccine produced a high level of neutralizing antibodies – Y-shaped proteins that bind to the coronavirus and block it from entering human cells. The vaccine was dosed at 50 micrograms, which is half of what is used among adults, but still produced on average 1.5 times as many antibodies in children as it did in young adults given the higher dose. The majority of adverse events were mild or moderate, including fatigue, headache, fever, and injection site pain. These early results, released via a press statement, do not yet include a vaccine efficacy estimate, which may be expected at a later time once cases have accrued. The Moderna news comes as the US Food and Drug Administration is preparing to convene a panel of advisors to vote on whether to greenlight the Pfizer shot for younger children, paving the way for 28 million more Americans to be vaccinated. A briefing document posted on the FDA’s website indicated the agency believes benefits outweigh the most worrying side effect for this age group, namely myocarditis, or heart inflammation. “The overall analysis predicted that the numbers of clinically significant COVID-19-related outcomes prevented would clearly outweigh the numbers of vaccine-associated excess myocarditis cases,” the document said. But it acknowledged the benefit-risk calculus would differ when community transmission is very low, as was the case in the United States in June 2021. The FDA also uploaded Pfizer’s efficacy analysis, with the company estimating a two-dose course of its vaccine at 10 micrograms was more than 90 percent effective in preventing symptomatic disease. Overall, more than 150 children aged 5 to 11 have died from Covid in the United States since the start of the pandemic, according to official data. “If all goes well, and we get the regulatory approval and the recommendation from the CDC, it’s entirely possible, if not very likely, that vaccines will be available for children from 5 to 11 within the first week or two of November,” Fauci told ABC News Sunday. (AFP)",,punchng,True,"[('United States', 'GPE'), ('Moderna', 'PERSON'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('COVID-19', 'PRODUCT'), ('6-11', 'DATE'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('Pfizer', 'PERSON'), ('5-11', 'DATE'), ('Anthony Fauci', 'PERSON'), ('mid-November', 'DATE'), ('6 to under 12 years', 'DATE'), ('Moderna', 'PERSON'), ('Stephane Bancel', 'PRODUCT'), ('4,753', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('half', 'CARDINAL'), ('1.5', 'CARDINAL'), ('FDA', 'ORG'), ('Pfizer', 'PERSON'), ('Moderna', 'PERSON'), ('the US Food and Drug Administration', 'ORG'), ('Pfizer', 'PERSON'), ('28 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('Americans', 'NORP'), ('FDA', 'ORG'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('June 2021', 'DATE'), ('FDA', 'ORG'), ('Pfizer', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('more than 90 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('more than 150', 'CARDINAL'), ('5 to 11', 'CARDINAL'), ('Covid', 'GPE'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('CDC', 'ORG'), ('5 to 11', 'CARDINAL'), ('the first week', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Fauci', 'ORG'), ('ABC News', 'ORG'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('AFP', 'ORG'), ('Moderna', 'PERSON'), ('COVID-19', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Healthwise', 'GPE')]"
What causes ADHD and can it be cured?,https://theconversation.com/what-causes-adhd-and-can-it-be-cured-170179,,"['Gregory Fabiano', ' Professor of Psychology', ' Florida International University']",,,"On average, two students in every U.S. classroom have ADHD. damircudic/E+ via Getty Images Curious Kids is a series for children of all ages. If you have a question you’d like an expert to answer, send it to curiouskidsus@theconversation.com. What causes ADHD and can it be cured? – Geneva B., age 17, Philippines Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder is a common, yet often misunderstood, mental health condition. Symptoms include inattention, overactivity and impulsivity – behaviors everyone experiences at one time or another. For people with ADHD, these behaviors happen frequently and interfere with everyday life at school, at home and everywhere else. ADHD affects more than 6 million U.S. children. People who have ADHD develop symptoms by age 12, and it usually continues into adolescence and young adulthood. The condition can affect people throughout their whole life. On average, two students in every U.S. classroom have it. It is important to note that ADHD is just one way of defining a person’s behavior. It has nothing to do with how smart you are or whether you can make friends or excel at sports, music or art, or about any other strengths. What does and doesn’t cause ADHD Nobody really knows exactly what causes ADHD. Scientists think that genes may play a role, but no one knows exactly how at this point. Based on years of research findings, scientists attribute this condition to a combination of how someone’s brain works and their personal environment. Research has cast more light on what does not cause ADHD. For example, findings do not support the widespread theories that excessive sugar or too much time on electronics are responsible for growth in the number of children diagnosed with the condition since 1990 – when it was detected in less than 2% of all U.S. children. Today, at least 9.4% of kids have this diagnosis. Based on all the research I’ve conducted and the other findings I’ve reviewed, I think this increase is caused by better identification and more awareness of ADHD in general, rather than an overall increase in ADHD. How parents interact with their child, likewise, does not cause ADHD. But children and adolescents with ADHD have many behaviors that require more parental involvement than their peers. Changing behaviors as therapy Most psychologists think about ADHD as a characteristic that, like eye color or height, can’t be changed. Doctors can’t cure ADHD, just like they can’t double the length of your legs. If someone had a hard time reaching a high shelf, would you tell them they just need to be taller? Of course not. But you could suggest they use a stepladder. The good news is there are ways that people with ADHD can overcome the challenges this condition brings. Evidence supports two distinct kinds of treatments. Behavioral therapy is typically implemented by parents and teachers working together. It includes setting clear goals and giving feedback on progress toward those goals, usually on a daily basis. Another feature is providing rewards or privileges when people with ADHD meet their goals. Among the most effective treatments is teaching parents how to pay more attention when their children do their schoolwork and chores and generally behave well. Parents and teachers can help kids by “catching them being good” – rather than through correction and punishment. As they get older, children and teens with ADHD can set goals for themselves and work hard to learn ways to keep organized and manage their day. Behavioral therapy makes a difference because ADHD works like a light operated by a dimmer switch. Rather than simply being turned on or off, it can be turned up to a bright level or dialed down to a faint glimmer. ADHD symptoms, similarly, can increase or decrease in response to particular situations and interactions. Medications can help Prescription stimulant drugs, such as Adderall and Ritalin, can help many people with ADHD focus longer. Like with all medications, however, some people can’t take them due to side effects. Some nonstimulant drugs are available, but they generally are less effective. Researchers have found that the best approach is when behavior therapy begins first, especially for young children with ADHD. ADHD can hinder big transitions. In childhood and young adulthood, that includes starting middle school or high school, learning to drive, going to college or entering the workforce. I believe that extra attention and treatment are usually required at those times. Many years of research have led me to believe people with ADHD can be successful in the long run when they, their families and their teachers work as hard as is necessary to build skills and change behavior patterns that complicate everyday life. It also helps when they get that support for as long as is needed. Hello, curious kids! Do you have a question you’d like an expert to answer? Ask an adult to send your question to CuriousKidsUS@theconversation.com. Please tell us your name, age and the city where you live. And since curiosity has no age limit – adults, let us know what you’re wondering, too. We won’t be able to answer every question, but we will do our best. Gregory Fabiano has led projects in the last three years that have received research funding from the Department of Education, Institute of Education Sciences, National Institutes of Health, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and Adlon Therapeutics. He has received royalty payments for published books from Guilford Publications and consultant payments from FastBridge/Illuminate.",2021-10-25 12:34:20,,,theconversation,True,"[('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('Getty Images Curious Kids', 'ORG'), ('Geneva B.', 'PERSON'), ('age 17', 'DATE'), ('Philippines Attention', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('more than 6 million', 'MONEY'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('age 12', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('years', 'DATE'), ('1990', 'DATE'), ('less than 2%', 'PERCENT'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('Today', 'DATE'), ('at least 9.4%', 'PERCENT'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('daily', 'DATE'), ('Adderall', 'PERSON'), ('Ritalin', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gregory Fabiano', 'PERSON'), ('the last three years', 'DATE'), ('the Department of Education', 'ORG'), ('Institute of Education Sciences', 'ORG'), ('National Institutes of Health', 'ORG'), ('the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention', 'ORG'), ('Adlon Therapeutics', 'ORG'), ('Guilford Publications', 'ORG'), ('FastBridge', 'ORG')]"
Biden balances vaccinating Americans and donating vaccines globally,https://www.npr.org/2021/10/25/1048918694/biden-balances-vaccinating-americans-and-donating-vaccines-globally,,,,"The U.S. delivered the 200 millionth dose of COVID-19 vaccines worldwide, part of a 1.1 billion dose pledge. NPR's Steve Inskeep talks to the State Department's Gayle Smith, who is leading the effort.","The U.S. delivered the 200 millionth dose of COVID-19 vaccines worldwide, part of a 1.1 billion dose pledge. NPR's Steve Inskeep talks to the State Department's Gayle Smith, who is leading the effort.",2021-10-25 09:10:00,,,npr,True,"[('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('200 millionth', 'DATE'), ('COVID-19', 'ORG'), ('1.1 billion', 'CARDINAL'), ('NPR', 'ORG'), ('Steve Inskeep', 'PERSON'), (""the State Department's"", 'ORG'), ('Gayle Smith', 'PERSON')]"
"Embrace safer alternatives to tobacco smoking, experts urge smokers",https://healthwise.punchng.com/embrace-safer-alternatives-to-tobacco-smoking-experts-urge-smokers/,"['News', '#cigarette smoking']",['Amarachi Okeh'],,"Amarachi Okeh Experts from Philip Morris International have urged smokers to embrace safer alternatives to tobacco smoking. According to the experts, smokers who are unable to quit smoking should consider heated tobacco products that do not involve the burning of tobacco. The experts made the call at a media briefing organised by Philip Morris International […] The post Embrace safer alternatives to tobacco smoking, experts urge smokers appeared first on Healthwise.","Amarachi Okeh Experts from Philip Morris International have urged smokers to embrace safer alternatives to tobacco smoking. According to the experts, smokers who are unable to quit smoking should consider heated tobacco products that do not involve the burning of tobacco. The experts made the call at a media briefing organised by Philip Morris International and held at Radisson Blu, Ikeja, Lagos on Saturday. Speaking at the media briefing, the head of Scientific Engagement, the Middle East and Africa region, Philip Morris International, Ignacho Gonzalez, who is a medical researcher, stated that the tobacco company is committed to encouraging safer alternatives to tobacco smoking. The company, Gonzalez said, is poised to introduce smoke-free products that would be be better alternatives for smokers who have been unable to quit smoking despite their best efforts. The media briefing had in attendance Director External Affairs sub-Saharan Africa PMI, Haruna Ly, Director External Affairs PMI, Nigeria, Mojisola Akpata, Manager of Communications of the region, PMI, Ms. Cecil, CEO Almack Media, Aliu Akoshile and Executive Chairman of All Africa Global Media, Amadou Mahtar Ba. Gonzalez, speaking virtually at the event noted that wh quitting smoking still remains the best choice for health. He, however, stressed that the PMI tobacco-heated products are better alternatives for people who are unable to quit smoking. “Our ambition and intent are to convince smokers who intend to continue smoking to switch to smoke-free products as soon as possible. “We want to move away from cigarettes as soon as possible. We want cigarettes to be obsolete, something of the past and we are doing everything that we can to get to the day where there are no more cigarettes as soon as possible.” According to the World Health Organisation, there are one billion smokers in the world. Gonzalez noted that despite efforts by governments and regulators to reduce the number of smokers by advocating the prevention and cessation of smoking cigarettes, the numbers still remain. According to Gonzalez, switching to heated tobacco products eliminates the combustion which tobacco passes through that causes danger in the health of smokers. He stated that discussions around tobacco should be steered towards harm reduction instead. “The government and regulators have tried to reduce the number of smokers by prevention and cessation. These measures have had success but still, there are one billion smokers out there so the question is what else can we do. “This is where the area of tobacco harm reduction as a third complementary pillar to the other two comes to play,” he said. Gonzalez noted that though switching to heated tobacco products does not completely eliminate the risks involved in smoking, they significantly reduce it. This, he said, is backed by evidence from 10 clinical studies conducted by PMI in different parts of the world. “When you look at these alternatives under the umbrella of harm reduction, if we want to achieve harm reduction, we need to think. “On one hand we need products that are less harmful than continuing to smoke and this needs to be demonstrated by the scientific side and at the same time we need products that are accepted by smokers so that they can switch because at the end of the day if you have a product that has great risk reduction but nobody uses it, you will not achieve harm reduction.” He added that in heated tobacco products, nicotine, a reason why many smokers still smoke, is present. He quashed the notion that nicotine is the primary cause of diseases from smoking. He posited that while nicotine is not risk-free, it is not the primary cause of diseases in smokers. “The primary cause of disease in a cigarette is actually the toxicants that are present in the smoke of a cigarette, the majority of which are generated when the tobacco burns,” he said. Also speaking, the Director, External Affairs at PMI, Nigeria, Mojisola Akpata called on the government to encourage safer alternatives to smoking. Akpata urged the Nigerian government to practice differentiated regulation in the tobacco industry and also provide education to smokers. The director of external affairs stated that the focus of the discussion on tobacco harm should now be focused on harm reduction instead of only prevention and cessation. She urged that regulators consider the third option supported by the WHO which is harm reduction. PMI, Akpata said, is leading the innovation to healthier alternatives to cigarette smoking by creating a range of alternatives such as e-cigarettes and other products that do not involve the burning of tobacco. According to Akpata, smoke is the primary cause of smoking-related diseases hence by eliminating burning, the levels of harmful chemicals generated can be significantly reduced. The company, Akpata said, does not want non-smokers to begin smoking, rather they are investing in reducing the risks caused by the combustion of tobacco to the health of smokers who cannot quit. “Harm reduction is what has led to all the research and development that we have had in this space moving from cigarettes to alternatives that are safer.” She stated that the discussion on moving to tobacco harm reduction makes sense because “it is scientifically substantiated that smokers who switch extend their life span.” “It’s good for public health. She added that since it applies in other industries the same thing should apply to tobacco companies. “We are trying to extend our time here on earth and for us to do that, it requires that the regulatory space allows for you to have harm reduction information available to legal age smokers. “A lot of countries are taking on the harm reduction mantra. It works for public health experts to say, you know what? We encourage e-cigarette as an option because it is a safer alternative. Although not totally safe, it is a reduced risk alternative to burning tobacco and that is the conversation that we are hoping that Africa and Nigeria will have soon. “However, you need to understand what the regulatory tools are to regulate the tobacco space and in regulating the tobacco space we are looking at the principles. “We believe that nicotine and tobacco should be regulated, youths and non-smokers should not use tobacco products. “We should have the options of choosing and you can only have that if you have the awareness and if there are regulations in place. Smokers should have access to information that would allow them to make informed decisions. “Regulations need to achieve a balance. Maximize the potential of adults to switch to a better alternative.” “While these tobacco heated products are yet to hit the Nigerian market, these are widely accepted even by regulatory bodies in Europe, America, and Asia while South Africa is the only Africa where heated tobacco products are available at the moment,” Akpata, said. Copyright PUNCH All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. Contact: health_wise@punchng.com   The post Embrace safer alternatives to tobacco smoking, experts urge smokers appeared first on Healthwise.",2021-10-25 08:53:25,"Amarachi Okeh Experts from Philip Morris International have urged smokers to embrace safer alternatives to tobacco smoking. According to the experts, smokers who are unable to quit smoking should consider heated tobacco products that do not involve the burning of tobacco. The experts made the call at a media briefing organised by Philip Morris International and held at Radisson Blu, Ikeja, Lagos on Saturday. Speaking at the media briefing, the head of Scientific Engagement, the Middle East and Africa region, Philip Morris International, Ignacho Gonzalez, who is a medical researcher, stated that the tobacco company is committed to encouraging safer alternatives to tobacco smoking. The company, Gonzalez said, is poised to introduce smoke-free products that would be be better alternatives for smokers who have been unable to quit smoking despite their best efforts. The media briefing had in attendance Director External Affairs sub-Saharan Africa PMI, Haruna Ly, Director External Affairs PMI, Nigeria, Mojisola Akpata, Manager of Communications of the region, PMI, Ms. Cecil, CEO Almack Media, Aliu Akoshile and Executive Chairman of All Africa Global Media, Amadou Mahtar Ba. Gonzalez, speaking virtually at the event noted that wh quitting smoking still remains the best choice for health. He, however, stressed that the PMI tobacco-heated products are better alternatives for people who are unable to quit smoking. “Our ambition and intent are to convince smokers who intend to continue smoking to switch to smoke-free products as soon as possible. “We want to move away from cigarettes as soon as possible. We want cigarettes to be obsolete, something of the past and we are doing everything that we can to get to the day where there are no more cigarettes as soon as possible.” According to the World Health Organisation, there are one billion smokers in the world. Gonzalez noted that despite efforts by governments and regulators to reduce the number of smokers by advocating the prevention and cessation of smoking cigarettes, the numbers still remain. According to Gonzalez, switching to heated tobacco products eliminates the combustion which tobacco passes through that causes danger in the health of smokers. He stated that discussions around tobacco should be steered towards harm reduction instead. “The government and regulators have tried to reduce the number of smokers by prevention and cessation. These measures have had success but still, there are one billion smokers out there so the question is what else can we do. “This is where the area of tobacco harm reduction as a third complementary pillar to the other two comes to play,” he said. Gonzalez noted that though switching to heated tobacco products does not completely eliminate the risks involved in smoking, they significantly reduce it. This, he said, is backed by evidence from 10 clinical studies conducted by PMI in different parts of the world. “When you look at these alternatives under the umbrella of harm reduction, if we want to achieve harm reduction, we need to think. “On one hand we need products that are less harmful than continuing to smoke and this needs to be demonstrated by the scientific side and at the same time we need products that are accepted by smokers so that they can switch because at the end of the day if you have a product that has great risk reduction but nobody uses it, you will not achieve harm reduction.” He added that in heated tobacco products, nicotine, a reason why many smokers still smoke, is present. He quashed the notion that nicotine is the primary cause of diseases from smoking. He posited that while nicotine is not risk-free, it is not the primary cause of diseases in smokers. “The primary cause of disease in a cigarette is actually the toxicants that are present in the smoke of a cigarette, the majority of which are generated when the tobacco burns,” he said. Also speaking, the Director, External Affairs at PMI, Nigeria, Mojisola Akpata called on the government to encourage safer alternatives to smoking. Akpata urged the Nigerian government to practice differentiated regulation in the tobacco industry and also provide education to smokers. The director of external affairs stated that the focus of the discussion on tobacco harm should now be focused on harm reduction instead of only prevention and cessation. She urged that regulators consider the third option supported by the WHO which is harm reduction. PMI, Akpata said, is leading the innovation to healthier alternatives to cigarette smoking by creating a range of alternatives such as e-cigarettes and other products that do not involve the burning of tobacco. According to Akpata, smoke is the primary cause of smoking-related diseases hence by eliminating burning, the levels of harmful chemicals generated can be significantly reduced. The company, Akpata said, does not want non-smokers to begin smoking, rather they are investing in reducing the risks caused by the combustion of tobacco to the health of smokers who cannot quit. “Harm reduction is what has led to all the research and development that we have had in this space moving from cigarettes to alternatives that are safer.” She stated that the discussion on moving to tobacco harm reduction makes sense because “it is scientifically substantiated that smokers who switch extend their life span.” “It’s good for public health. She added that since it applies in other industries the same thing should apply to tobacco companies. “We are trying to extend our time here on earth and for us to do that, it requires that the regulatory space allows for you to have harm reduction information available to legal age smokers. “A lot of countries are taking on the harm reduction mantra. It works for public health experts to say, you know what? We encourage e-cigarette as an option because it is a safer alternative. Although not totally safe, it is a reduced risk alternative to burning tobacco and that is the conversation that we are hoping that Africa and Nigeria will have soon. “However, you need to understand what the regulatory tools are to regulate the tobacco space and in regulating the tobacco space we are looking at the principles. “We believe that nicotine and tobacco should be regulated, youths and non-smokers should not use tobacco products. “We should have the options of choosing and you can only have that if you have the awareness and if there are regulations in place. Smokers should have access to information that would allow them to make informed decisions. “Regulations need to achieve a balance. Maximize the potential of adults to switch to a better alternative.” “While these tobacco heated products are yet to hit the Nigerian market, these are widely accepted even by regulatory bodies in Europe, America, and Asia while South Africa is the only Africa where heated tobacco products are available at the moment,” Akpata, said. Copyright PUNCH All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. Contact: [email protected]",,punchng,True,"[('Philip Morris International', 'ORG'), ('Philip Morris International', 'ORG'), ('Radisson Blu', 'FAC'), ('Ikeja', 'GPE'), ('Lagos', 'GPE'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Scientific Engagement', 'ORG'), ('the Middle East', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Philip Morris International', 'ORG'), ('Ignacho Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('PMI', 'ORG'), ('Haruna Ly', 'PERSON'), ('PMI', 'ORG'), ('Nigeria', 'GPE'), ('Mojisola Akpata', 'ORG'), ('PMI', 'ORG'), ('Cecil', 'PERSON'), ('Almack Media', 'PERSON'), ('Aliu Akoshile', 'PERSON'), ('Amadou Mahtar Ba', 'PERSON'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('PMI', 'ORG'), ('the day', 'DATE'), ('the World Health Organisation', 'ORG'), ('one billion smokers', 'QUANTITY'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('one billion', 'QUANTITY'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('PMI', 'ORG'), ('the end of the day', 'DATE'), ('External Affairs', 'ORG'), ('PMI', 'ORG'), ('Nigeria', 'GPE'), ('Mojisola Akpata', 'ORG'), ('Akpata', 'ORG'), ('Nigerian', 'NORP'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('WHO', 'ORG'), ('PMI', 'ORG'), ('Akpata', 'ORG'), ('Akpata', 'ORG'), ('Akpata', 'ORG'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Nigeria', 'GPE'), ('Nigerian', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('America', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('South Africa', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Akpata', 'ORG'), ('PUNCH', 'ORG'), ('Embrace', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Healthwise', 'GPE')]"
"Pandemic not over with almost 50,000 COVID-19 related deaths weekly –WHO",https://healthwise.punchng.com/pandemic-not-over-with-almost-50000-covid-19-related-deaths-weekly-who/,"['News', '#WHO COVID-19 Update']",['Lara Adejoro'],,"Lara Adejoro The World Health Organisation says the rate at which countries are reporting COVID-19 death-related cases, the pandemic is far from being over. The Director-General of WHO, Dr. Tedros Ghebreyesus said this in his address at the World Health Summit on Sunday. According to him, the pandemic will end when the world chooses to […] The post Pandemic not over with almost 50,000 COVID-19 related deaths weekly –WHO appeared first on Healthwise.","Lara Adejoro The World Health Organisation says the rate at which countries are reporting COVID-19 death-related cases, the pandemic is far from being over. The Director-General of WHO, Dr. Tedros Ghebreyesus said this in his address at the World Health Summit on Sunday. According to him, the pandemic will end when the world chooses to end it. “Twelve years since the first World Health Summit, we meet once again in the shadow of a pandemic. And we are faced once again with some very big questions: some of the same ones we were asking in 2009 that remain unanswered, and some new ones. “One of the questions I am asked most often is: when will the pandemic end? My answer is that the pandemic will end when the world chooses to end it. It’s in our hands. We have all the tools we need: effective public health tools and effective medical tools. “But the world has not used those tools well. With almost 50 thousand deaths a week, the pandemic is far from over – and that’s just the reported deaths,” Ghebreyesus said. The WHO chief noted that the target to vaccinate 40 percent of the population of every country by the end of this year is reachable if the countries and companies that control supply match their statements with actions. “The barrier is not production. The barriers are politics and profit. It’s clear what needs to happen. The countries that have already reached the 40 percent target – including all G20 countries – must give their place in the vaccine delivery queue to COVAX and the African Vaccines Acquisition Trust, or AVAT; The G20 countries must fulfil their dose-sharing commitments immediately. “Manufacturers must prioritize and fulfil their contracts with COVAX and AVAT as a matter of urgency, and be far more transparent about what is going where. “And they must share know-how, technology, and licences, and waive intellectual property rights. We’re not asking for charity; we’re calling for a common-sense investment in the global recovery,” he said. He urged countries to end the pandemic by pulling out all the stops to reach the target of vaccinating 40 percent of the population by the end of this year. “The pandemic has demonstrated beyond doubt that health is not a luxury for the rich, or simply an outcome of development; it’s a fundamental human right, and the basis of social, economic, and political stability. “There’s only one way to achieve these three things – and that’s together. No country can end the pandemic in isolation from the rest of the world. And no country can protect the health of its own people without working to protect the health of all people. “It takes some tough negotiations and some tough decisions. But the reward is a world that is healthier, safer, and fairer for all of us,” he noted. Copyright PUNCH All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. Contact: health_wise@punchng.com The post Pandemic not over with almost 50,000 COVID-19 related deaths weekly –WHO appeared first on Healthwise.",2021-10-25 08:41:55,"Lara Adejoro The World Health Organisation says the rate at which countries are reporting COVID-19 death-related cases, the pandemic is far from being over. The Director-General of WHO, Dr. Tedros Ghebreyesus said this in his address at the World Health Summit on Sunday. According to him, the pandemic will end when the world chooses to end it. “Twelve years since the first World Health Summit, we meet once again in the shadow of a pandemic. And we are faced once again with some very big questions: some of the same ones we were asking in 2009 that remain unanswered, and some new ones. “One of the questions I am asked most often is: when will the pandemic end? My answer is that the pandemic will end when the world chooses to end it. It’s in our hands. We have all the tools we need: effective public health tools and effective medical tools. “But the world has not used those tools well. With almost 50 thousand deaths a week, the pandemic is far from over – and that’s just the reported deaths,” Ghebreyesus said. The WHO chief noted that the target to vaccinate 40 percent of the population of every country by the end of this year is reachable if the countries and companies that control supply match their statements with actions. “The barrier is not production. The barriers are politics and profit. It’s clear what needs to happen. The countries that have already reached the 40 percent target – including all G20 countries – must give their place in the vaccine delivery queue to COVAX and the African Vaccines Acquisition Trust, or AVAT; The G20 countries must fulfil their dose-sharing commitments immediately. “Manufacturers must prioritize and fulfil their contracts with COVAX and AVAT as a matter of urgency, and be far more transparent about what is going where. “And they must share know-how, technology, and licences, and waive intellectual property rights. We’re not asking for charity; we’re calling for a common-sense investment in the global recovery,” he said. He urged countries to end the pandemic by pulling out all the stops to reach the target of vaccinating 40 percent of the population by the end of this year. “The pandemic has demonstrated beyond doubt that health is not a luxury for the rich, or simply an outcome of development; it’s a fundamental human right, and the basis of social, economic, and political stability. “There’s only one way to achieve these three things – and that’s together. No country can end the pandemic in isolation from the rest of the world. And no country can protect the health of its own people without working to protect the health of all people. “It takes some tough negotiations and some tough decisions. But the reward is a world that is healthier, safer, and fairer for all of us,” he noted. Copyright PUNCH All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. Contact: [email protected]",,punchng,True,"[('Lara Adejoro The World Health Organisation', 'ORG'), ('Tedros Ghebreyesus', 'PERSON'), ('the World Health Summit', 'ORG'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Twelve years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('World Health Summit', 'EVENT'), ('2009', 'DATE'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('almost 50 thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ghebreyesus', 'PERSON'), ('WHO', 'ORG'), ('40 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('the end of this year', 'DATE'), ('the 40 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('G20', 'ORG'), ('the African Vaccines Acquisition Trust', 'ORG'), ('AVAT', 'ORG'), ('G20', 'ORG'), ('AVAT', 'ORG'), ('40 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('the end of this year', 'DATE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('PUNCH', 'ORG'), ('almost 50,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('weekly', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Healthwise', 'GPE')]"
"Get vaccinated against COVID-19, Edo govt urges residents",https://healthwise.punchng.com/get-vaccinated-against-covid-19-edo-govt-urges-residents/,"['News', '#COVID-19 vaccination in Edo State']",['healthwise'],,"Adeyinka Adedipe The Edo State Government has urged residents to complement the government’s efforts at containing the COVID-19 pandemic by getting vaccinated. The state’s COVID-19 Incident Manager, Dr. Andrew Obi, gave the charge while addressing journalists in Benin City on Sunday. Obi, who reassured all of the government’s commitment to ensuring the health and safety […] The post Get vaccinated against COVID-19, Edo govt urges residents appeared first on Healthwise.","Adeyinka Adedipe The Edo State Government has urged residents to complement the government’s efforts at containing the COVID-19 pandemic by getting vaccinated. The state’s COVID-19 Incident Manager, Dr. Andrew Obi, gave the charge while addressing journalists in Benin City on Sunday. Obi, who reassured all of the government’s commitment to ensuring the health and safety of citizens, reiterated the need for all residents to continue to comply with protocols. He said it was important for all residents to be vaccinated to stay alive and healthy, as more unvaccinated persons continue to die from the virus. Obi noted that all persons who have died from the virus during the third wave of the pandemic in the state were unvaccinated, while over 96 per cent of confirmed cases are those who were never vaccinated. He said, “While the government intensifies efforts to contain the pandemic and ensure the safety of Edo citizens, we charge everyone who has been administered with the first dose of AstraZeneca vaccine, to come out for the second dose to get full protection against the virus, while others who have not been vaccinated are encouraged to come out and get the vaccination, as the vaccines are safe, free and effective. “Also, all citizens must continue to comply with all basic preventive measures including frequent handwashing with soap under running water, avoiding close contacts and ensuring regular use of face masks.” The post Get vaccinated against COVID-19, Edo govt urges residents appeared first on Healthwise.",2021-10-25 08:01:29,"Adeyinka Adedipe The Edo State Government has urged residents to complement the government’s efforts at containing the COVID-19 pandemic by getting vaccinated. The state’s COVID-19 Incident Manager, Dr. Andrew Obi, gave the charge while addressing journalists in Benin City on Sunday. Obi, who reassured all of the government’s commitment to ensuring the health and safety of citizens, reiterated the need for all residents to continue to comply with protocols. He said it was important for all residents to be vaccinated to stay alive and healthy, as more unvaccinated persons continue to die from the virus. Obi noted that all persons who have died from the virus during the third wave of the pandemic in the state were unvaccinated, while over 96 per cent of confirmed cases are those who were never vaccinated. He said, “While the government intensifies efforts to contain the pandemic and ensure the safety of Edo citizens, we charge everyone who has been administered with the first dose of AstraZeneca vaccine, to come out for the second dose to get full protection against the virus, while others who have not been vaccinated are encouraged to come out and get the vaccination, as the vaccines are safe, free and effective. “Also, all citizens must continue to comply with all basic preventive measures including frequent handwashing with soap under running water, avoiding close contacts and ensuring regular use of face masks.”",,punchng,True,"[('Adeyinka Adedipe', 'ORG'), ('The Edo State Government', 'ORG'), ('COVID-19', 'ORG'), ('COVID-19 Incident', 'ORG'), ('Andrew Obi', 'PERSON'), ('Benin City', 'GPE'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('96 per cent', 'MONEY'), ('Edo', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('AstraZeneca', 'PRODUCT'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('COVID-19', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Healthwise', 'GPE')]"
COVID doesn't need to run rampant. Here are 6 ways to keep cases low in the next year,https://theconversation.com/covid-doesnt-need-to-run-rampant-here-are-6-ways-to-keep-cases-low-in-the-next-year-170207,,"['Brendan Crabb', ' Director and CEO', ' Burnet Institute']",,,"In the blink of an eye, we’ve gone from 18 months of zero tolerance for COVID to accepting huge case numbers as the norm for Australia’s foreseeable future. Our ambitions are now limited to simply keeping a lid on things to avoid our health systems being overwhelmed – not that we’ve defined what that limit is. But how many lives, severe illnesses, and cases of long COVID are we willing to accept? The national and other roadmaps aren’t explicit about this. NSW and Victoria have regularly seen 10-15 lives lost each day to COVID, so this could represent the baseline rather than the cap. The impact of long COVID simply isn’t considered in the risk-benefit equation. It’s time to draw breath and consider a better alternative. High case numbers aren’t our only path to freedom. It’s not inevitable all Australians will get COVID in the near future. We could keep numbers low now and move to a strategy of eliminating the virus, like we do for measles, mumps, rubella and whooping cough, just to name a few. A strategy of local COVID elimination shouldn’t be taboo when it’s the norm for many other infectious diseases. Why do high case numbers matter if we’re all vaccinated? COVID vaccines are truly brilliant, especially against severe disease. They provide the essential base to move away from harsh public health measures. But like any medical intervention, they’re not perfect, even against severe illness. You aren’t bulletproof if you’ve had two doses. In fact, as Health Minister Greg Hunt announced last week, you’ll probably need a third dose soon. What’s more, releasing restrictions across the country is based on vaccination targets for those over 16 years. But reaching 70% and 80% targets leaves 30% or 20% of people unvaccinated and at risk in this group alone. Importantly this will include pockets of communities with much lower vaccination levels than others. Plus all children under 12 will be unvaccinated. Together, that’s 5-10 million unvaccinated Australians. Let’s be clear, the virus is and will be in our community for some time. This is sometimes inaccurately described as “endemic”, as in, a settled and predictable infection. COVID isn’t that yet, and we have no idea when it will be. COVID will remain epidemic for some time, characterised by bursts in at-risk communities and pockets of under-vaccinated people, because of waning immunity or new variants. If not countered, this epidemic scenario will continue to disrupt our health and economy. So, we need a ‘vaccines-plus’ strategy Keeping COVID numbers low presents a substantial challenge, especially in deeply fatigued NSW and Victoria. But as OzSAGE, an Australian network of scientists providing advice on COVID, has detailed, it can be achieved with a deliberate “vaccines-plus” strategy. The “plus” includes a range of minimally disruptive measures to keep transmission down, such as improving ventilation and maintaining the use of masks in higher risk settings. Victoria’s schools’ package is the best current example of appropriate ambition in this space. International examples tell us vaccines-plus works vastly better than vaccine-only. Keeping numbers low also presents a positive-feedback loop as it enables a functioning test, trace, isolate and quarantine system that’s crucial to keeping a lid on numbers. Keeping numbers low now doesn’t just delay the inevitable. In fact, a major motivation for holding the line is the future will be much better. Six ways to strengthen our COVID defences In 12 months’ time, the tools for interrupting transmission and managing COVID as a sporadic infectious disease will be substantially stronger than they are now. A realistic vision for a year from now includes: 1. Vastly improved vaccination Three shots will be routine and 80-90% of the whole population will be fully vaccinated in this way. Kids over five will also immunised, and we’ll be on the way to approving vaccines for those under five. This goal is likely to be achieved in six months rather than 12. We’ll be able to identify people who need further boosters using “immunity tests”, which provide a surrogate measure of people’s immunity. These are being developed by the Burnet and Doherty Institutes. Vaccines will prevent much more transmission than they do now. 2. Much less airborne transmission Clean air will be provided in risky indoor settings in a regulated and accepted way. Indoor density limits, and improved, targeted mask-wearing will be normalised in settings like public transport and schools. 3. New treatments Advances in therapy are likely to change the game completely. These could be simple pills or inhalers. For example, Australia recently purchased Merck’s COVID pill “molnupiravir”, which the company said halved the risk of hospitalisation and death. This is just a taster of what’s to come. Read more: Take-at-home COVID drug molnupiravir may be on its way — but vaccination is still our first line of defence 4. Improved test, trace, isolate and quarantine People who have COVID will easily and quickly know they’re positive and stay home while infectious. Our test, trace, isolate and quarantine systems will be functional and modernised, perhaps even using artificial intelligence. Self-testing, at home and elsewhere, will be widespread. 5. Traffic light quarantine system Borders will be open but risk-assessed. High-risk travellers will still have some form of quarantine. This is especially important to keep new variants at bay. 6. Reduced COVID in the region It’s really not an option for the developed world to let infections run free in low-income countries. COVID doesn’t need to run rampant Letting COVID run is a risky experiment and most countries with greater experience of the impact of COVID infections have rejected this approach. An ambitious attitude to elimination can be achieved with a vaccines-plus strategy now and embracing innovations as they inevitably come. The second-best pandemic outcome is for most Australians to be fully vaccinated before they encounter the virus for the first time. After 18 months of monumental effort, and to this country’s enduring credit, this objective will be achieved. But there’s an even more important end goal for our health, free society, and economy – for most Australians to never encounter the virus at all, or if they do, to not be infected by it. In 12 months’ time, our defence against COVID will be stronger. We need a vaccines-plus strategy to safely get us there. In his capacity as a medical researcher and Burnet Institute Director, Brendan Crabb receives funding from the Australian government and several State governments for work on COVID-19 and other health problems. He is also the Chair of three peak body advocacy agencies; the Australian Global Health Alliance, the Pacific Friends of Global Health and the Victorian Chapter of the Australian Association of Medical Research Institutes. He is affiliated with OzSAGE.Nancy Baxter receives funding from the Canadian Institutes for Health Research to evaluate the impact of COVID on obstetrical care. She is affiliated with OzSAGE.",2021-10-24 19:00:32,,,theconversation,True,"[('18 months', 'DATE'), ('zero', 'CARDINAL'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('Victoria', 'GPE'), ('10-15', 'CARDINAL'), ('each day', 'DATE'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('Australians', 'NORP'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Health', 'ORG'), ('Greg Hunt', 'PERSON'), ('last week', 'DATE'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('16 years', 'DATE'), ('70%', 'PERCENT'), ('80%', 'PERCENT'), ('30% or', 'PERCENT'), ('20%', 'PERCENT'), ('under 12', 'DATE'), ('Australians', 'NORP'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('Keeping COVID', 'PERSON'), ('NSW', 'ORG'), ('Victoria', 'GPE'), ('OzSAGE', 'ORG'), ('Australian', 'NORP'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('Victoria’s', 'PERSON'), ('Six', 'CARDINAL'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('12 months', 'DATE'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('a year from now', 'DATE'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('80-90%', 'PERCENT'), ('over five', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('six months', 'DATE'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Doherty Institutes', 'ORG'), ('Vaccines', 'ORG'), ('2.', 'CARDINAL'), ('3.', 'CARDINAL'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('Merck', 'ORG'), ('molnupiravir', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Borders', 'ORG'), ('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Australians', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('18 months', 'DATE'), ('Australians', 'NORP'), ('12 months', 'DATE'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('Burnet Institute', 'ORG'), ('Brendan Crabb', 'PERSON'), ('Australian', 'NORP'), ('State', 'ORG'), ('COVID-19', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Australian Global Health Alliance', 'ORG'), ('the Pacific Friends of Global Health', 'ORG'), ('the Australian Association of Medical Research Institutes', 'ORG'), ('the Canadian Institutes for Health Research', 'ORG'), ('COVID', 'PERSON'), ('OzSAGE', 'ORG')]"
"Gombe donates insecticide-treated nets, drugs to prison inmates",https://healthwise.punchng.com/gombe-donates-insecticide-treated-nets-drugs-to-prison-inmates/,"['News', 'Gombe State']",['Chima Azubuike'],,"Chima Azubuike The Gombe State Ministry of Health has donated 150 Insecticide Treated Nets and medications to inmates in the state’s correctional facility. Speaking during the presentation of the relief items to inmates, alongside officials of the Society for Family Health, Gombe State Health Commissioner, Dr. Habu Dahiru, said the donation would go a long […] The post Gombe donates insecticide-treated nets, drugs to prison inmates appeared first on Healthwise.","Chima Azubuike The Gombe State Ministry of Health has donated 150 Insecticide Treated Nets and medications to inmates in the state’s correctional facility. Speaking during the presentation of the relief items to inmates, alongside officials of the Society for Family Health, Gombe State Health Commissioner, Dr. Habu Dahiru, said the donation would go a long way in complementing the effort of government towards ensuring quality health and malaria prevention in the state. Other donated items include magnesium and ORS salt. Dahiru said that the visit was to ensure inmates in correctional facilities get quality healthcare delivery, adding that they are entitled to enjoy quality health services as inmates in the state. Recall that recently Gombe state through the National Malaria Elimination Programme started the distribution of 2.3 million ITNs. “That is part of measures by Gombe state to tackle the burden of malaria,” Dahiru said. Responding, Gombe State Correctional Service Controller, Muhammad Garba, lauded the Ministry and SFH for their efforts to improve the health and well-being of citizens of the state including inmates. While assuring the team that the insecticide-treated nets would be used by the inmates, Garba also appeal for the donation of blood pressure checking apparatus as well as thermometers. He said, “I want to assure that the equipment donated will be distributed to the inmates accordingly. I also wish to request for BP apparatus and thermometers for the inmates.” Speaking earlier, Project Manager, Gombe State Agency for the Control of AIDS, Dr. Suraj Abdulkarim described the gesture as a success and called on the stakeholders in the health sector to continue partnering with both government and non-governmental organisations to improve the quality of health care services. Suraj added, “GOMSACA will continue to contribute its quota to the inmates as we had done in the year 2019 especially to those who are living with HIV /AIDS.” Copyright PUNCH All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. Contact: health_wise@punchng.com The post Gombe donates insecticide-treated nets, drugs to prison inmates appeared first on Healthwise.",2021-10-24 11:06:32,"Chima Azubuike The Gombe State Ministry of Health has donated 150 Insecticide Treated Nets and medications to inmates in the state’s correctional facility. Speaking during the presentation of the relief items to inmates, alongside officials of the Society for Family Health, Gombe State Health Commissioner, Dr. Habu Dahiru, said the donation would go a long way in complementing the effort of government towards ensuring quality health and malaria prevention in the state. Other donated items include magnesium and ORS salt. Dahiru said that the visit was to ensure inmates in correctional facilities get quality healthcare delivery, adding that they are entitled to enjoy quality health services as inmates in the state. Recall that recently Gombe state through the National Malaria Elimination Programme started the distribution of 2.3 million ITNs. “That is part of measures by Gombe state to tackle the burden of malaria,” Dahiru said. Responding, Gombe State Correctional Service Controller, Muhammad Garba, lauded the Ministry and SFH for their efforts to improve the health and well-being of citizens of the state including inmates. While assuring the team that the insecticide-treated nets would be used by the inmates, Garba also appeal for the donation of blood pressure checking apparatus as well as thermometers. He said, “I want to assure that the equipment donated will be distributed to the inmates accordingly. I also wish to request for BP apparatus and thermometers for the inmates.” Speaking earlier, Project Manager, Gombe State Agency for the Control of AIDS, Dr. Suraj Abdulkarim described the gesture as a success and called on the stakeholders in the health sector to continue partnering with both government and non-governmental organisations to improve the quality of health care services. Suraj added, “GOMSACA will continue to contribute its quota to the inmates as we had done in the year 2019 especially to those who are living with HIV /AIDS.” Copyright PUNCH All rights reserved. This material, and other digital content on this website, may not be reproduced, published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed in whole or in part without prior express written permission from PUNCH. Contact: [email protected]",,punchng,True,"[('Chima Azubuike', 'PERSON'), ('150', 'CARDINAL'), ('Insecticide Treated Nets', 'ORG'), ('the Society for Family Health', 'ORG'), ('Gombe State Health', 'ORG'), ('Habu Dahiru', 'PERSON'), ('ORS', 'ORG'), ('Dahiru', 'PERSON'), ('the National Malaria Elimination Programme', 'ORG'), ('2.3 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dahiru', 'PERSON'), ('Gombe State Correctional Service Controller', 'ORG'), ('Muhammad Garba', 'PERSON'), ('SFH', 'ORG'), ('Garba', 'ORG'), ('BP', 'ORG'), ('Gombe State Agency', 'ORG'), ('the Control of AIDS', 'ORG'), ('Suraj Abdulkarim', 'PERSON'), ('Suraj', 'ORG'), ('GOMSACA', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the year 2019', 'DATE'), ('PUNCH', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Healthwise', 'GPE')]"
Facebook removes just three per cent of hate posts according to a whistleblower,https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/politics/16531829/facebook-removes-just-three-hate-posts-whistleblower/,"['Politics', 'Facebook']",['Jonathan Reilly'],,"FACEBOOK removes less than three per cent of violent hate-filled posts, a whistleblower said last night. Former Facebook exec Frances Haugen, 37 blew open Facebook’s claim that they remove nearly all bile-spewing posts, telling MPs the social network is very good at “dancing with the data.” And she said the tech giant is “unquestionably, it’s […]","FACEBOOK removes less than three per cent of violent hate-filled posts, a whistleblower said last night. Former Facebook exec Frances Haugen, 37 blew open Facebook’s claim that they remove nearly all bile-spewing posts, telling MPs the social network is very good at “dancing with the data.” AFPFrances Haugen speaking to MPs[/caption] APFacebook has come under fire for not protecting users[/caption] And she said the tech giant is “unquestionably, it’s making hate worse” by driving it’s users to political extremes, enabling bullies and forcing anorexia content onto young girls – all in the name of profit. Facebook claims it removes 97 per cent of hateful posts, but Ms Haugen said that was just hate that their computers found. She said one of the reasons Facebook’s bots failed to pick up hate was because they could not recognise regional dialects. Giving an example she said: “UK English is sufficiently different that I would be unsurprised if the safety systems that they developed primarily for American English were actually under-enforcing in the UK.” In an explosive hearing, she said social network is “hurting the most vulnerable among us” and leading people down “rabbit holes.” Ms Haugen also met with Ian Russell the father of Molly Russel – the 14 year-old who killed herself after watching self-harm videos on Instagram. Chillingling she told MPs: “The algorithms take people who have very mainstream interests and they push them towards extreme interests. Adding: “Someone looking for healthy recipes will get pushed towards anorexia content.” And she said bullying follows children home from school and carries on in their bedrooms at night via Instagram, a whistleblower has claimed. She said: “When I was in high school, it didn’t matter if your experience in high school was horrible, most kids had good homes to go home to and they could at the end of the day disconnect, they would get a break for 16 hours. “Facebook’s own research says now the bullying follows children home, it goes into their bedrooms. “The last thing they see at night is someone being cruel to them. “The first thing they see in the morning is a hateful statement and that is just so much worse.” Ms Patel held a “constructive meeting” on online safety with Ms Haugen before her meeting with MPs. She said after “tech companies have a moral duty to keep their users safe” Most read in Politics PAY RISE £1,000 a year boost to wages as Rishi hikes minimum wage to £9.50 an hour 'TOUCH AND GO' PM admits he's 'very worried' leaders may FAIL to get global COP26 deal TEST THE SEASON Xmas WILL be 'normal' but Brits should test before seeing elderly relatives END HATE Furious MPs order social media firms to adopt 'no tolerance approach' to hate KIDS' WIN Funding for disabled kids will triple in win for The Sun's Give It Back campaign LONGER LESSONS Schools should stay open until 5pm so kids can catch up, says education czar But Ms Haugen refused to label the actions of the company as “evil” or “malevolent”, but said there was a “pattern of inadequacy.” Facebook and other social media companies will also speak to the daft Online Safety Bill committee later this week. Andy Burrows, Head of Child Safety Online Policy, at the NSPCC, said the evidence showed that “safety is simply not a priority for those at the top of Facebook.” He said: “She was also explicit about the scale of the challenge needed to make the company’s services safe for children after years of putting profit and growth first.”",2021-10-25 17:09:08,,,thesun,True,"[('less than three', 'CARDINAL'), ('last night', 'TIME'), ('Frances Haugen', 'PERSON'), ('37', 'CARDINAL'), ('Facebook’s', 'ORG'), ('97 per cent', 'MONEY'), ('Ms Haugen', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Facebook’s', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('Ms Haugen', 'PERSON'), ('Ian Russell', 'PERSON'), ('Molly Russel', 'PERSON'), ('14 year-old', 'DATE'), ('Instagram', 'ORG'), ('night', 'TIME'), ('Instagram', 'ORG'), ('the end of the day', 'DATE'), ('16 hours', 'TIME'), ('Facebook’s', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('night', 'TIME'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ms Patel', 'PERSON'), ('Ms Haugen', 'PERSON'), ('Politics PAY', 'ORG'), ('1,000', 'MONEY'), ('Rishi', 'ORG'), ('9.50', 'MONEY'), ('Xmas', 'PERSON'), ('Brits', 'NORP'), (""The Sun's Give It Back"", 'ORG'), ('LONGER', 'NORP'), ('Schools', 'PERSON'), ('5pm', 'TIME'), ('Ms Haugen', 'PERSON'), ('Online Safety Bill', 'PRODUCT'), ('later this week', 'DATE'), ('Andy Burrows', 'PERSON'), ('NSPCC', 'ORG'), ('years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')]"
"Christmas WILL go ahead as ‘normal’ but Brits should take tests before visiting elderly relatives, warns Sajid Javid",https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/16525167/christmas-normal-test-elderly-relatives-sajid-javid/,"['News', 'Politics', 'Christmas 2021', 'Coronavirus', 'UK Lockdown']",['Nicholas Gutteridge'],,"BRITS will be able to enjoy a “normal” Christmas this year but should self-test before visiting elderly relatives, Sajid Javid said today. The health secretary insisted the festive season will be “safe” so long as enough people get out and take their booster jabs. He dismissed Labour’s calls for Plan B restrictions including mask wearing, […]","BRITS will be able to enjoy a “normal” Christmas this year but should self-test before visiting elderly relatives, Sajid Javid said today. The health secretary insisted the festive season will be “safe” so long as enough people get out and take their booster jabs. ReutersSajid Javid insisted Brits will enjoy a ‘normal’ Christmas[/caption] AlamyThe health sec urged people to take tests before visiting elderly relatives[/caption] He dismissed Labour’s calls for Plan B restrictions including mask wearing, working from home, and vaccine passports to be triggered now. And he called on the five millions Brits who haven’t yet had the vaccine at all to come forward this winter. Asked if he agrees with Boris Johnson that this Christmas will be much better than last year’s, he replied: “Yes, of course. “For all of those like me hoping and planning for a normal Christmas – I do think that’s where we’ll be – if you want that let’s keep playing our part.” Mr Javid said people should “be cautious and take sensible actions to try and prevent the spread of the virus” as winter closes in. In particular he urged people to start taking Lateral Flow Tests before going to visit elderly relatives. He also said Brits should wear masks in crowded public places and keep up basic hygiene practices like hand washing. No Plan B Mr Javid insisted the pandemic data doesn’t yet show that the Government needs to trigger Plan B. He said: “We are not at that point. Whether we get there or not, we will see. “But the best thing we can all do to try and prevent us moving to Plan B or taking any further measures is to get out there and get our vaccines.” The health secretary also said he is “leaning towards” making jabs mandatory for all NHS workers within weeks. His remarks came after NHS England’s top doctor urged Brits to get their booster jabs to save festive celebrations. Professor Stephen Powis said people must “take up the offer” of a third dose to “protect the freedom and Christmas that we have all earned”. Mr Javid said the booster rollout has “picked up substantially” in recent days as more and more people come forward. A record 800,000 jabs were administered during the final three days of last week, including 325,140 on Saturday alone. And the PM was also handed another major boost as scientists predicted Covid cases will plummet within weeks without the need for Plan B. Experts believe the number of new infections could sink from 50,000 a day now to just 5,000 in time for Christmas. Most read in News GRIEF BEYOND WORDS Halyna Hutchins' son, 9, 'fell silent' after Alec Baldwin killed his mum PAY IS LOOKING UP Salary rise for 5m as Rishi ends public sector freeze & hikes min wage OF-FENCE-IVE Neighbour puts up 8ft fence next to family’s home… plunging them into darkness COINING IT Collector arrested for using £100 coin to buy fuel at Tesco wins £5,000 payout GRIM TOLL UK daily Covid cases rise by 39,962 in 24 hours amid fears WFH & masks may return CALL FOR HELP Family forced to sleep on sofa with kids for 2 YEARS beg council for help One model, from the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, suggests cases will peak shortly then fall off in the winter. Other unpublished models are also said to show infections nosediving, The Telegraph understands. But scientists warned new cases could start to rise again in the Spring as the immunity provided by booster jabs wears off.  ",2021-10-25 07:43:23,,,thesun,True,"[('Christmas', 'DATE'), ('this year', 'DATE'), ('Sajid Javid', 'PERSON'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('ReutersSajid Javid', 'PERSON'), ('Brits', 'NORP'), ('sec', 'ORG'), ('Labour', 'ORG'), ('five millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('Brits', 'NORP'), ('this winter', 'DATE'), ('Boris Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('this Christmas', 'DATE'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('Christmas', 'DATE'), ('’s', 'NORP'), ('Javid', 'PERSON'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('Brits', 'NORP'), ('Javid', 'PERSON'), ('Government', 'ORG'), ('Plan B.', 'PERSON'), ('NHS', 'ORG'), ('within weeks', 'DATE'), ('NHS England’s', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Brits', 'NORP'), ('Stephen Powis', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('the freedom and Christmas', 'DATE'), ('Javid', 'PERSON'), ('recent days', 'DATE'), ('A record 800,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('three days of last week', 'DATE'), ('325,140', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Covid', 'PERSON'), ('weeks', 'DATE'), ('50,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('5,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christmas', 'DATE'), (""Halyna Hutchins'"", 'PERSON'), ('9', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alec Baldwin', 'PERSON'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rishi', 'NORP'), ('8', 'CARDINAL'), ('100', 'MONEY'), ('Tesco', 'ORG'), ('5,000', 'MONEY'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('Covid', 'PERSON'), ('39,962', 'CARDINAL'), ('24 hours', 'TIME'), ('WFH &', 'ORG'), ('2 YEARS', 'DATE'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine', 'ORG'), ('the winter', 'DATE'), ('Telegraph', 'ORG'), ('the Spring', 'DATE')]"
Assemblymember Buffy Wicks discusses California vaccine mandates,https://ktla.com/news/politics/inside-california-politics/assemblymember-buffy-wicks-discusses-california-vaccine-mandates/,"['California', 'Inside California Politics', 'Local news', 'News', 'Politics', 'Buffy Wicks', 'California Department of Public Health']",['Inside California Politics '],,"Frank Buckley talks with California Assemblymember Buffy Wicks on vaccine mandates and how people may abuse personal exemptions. ""Yes, people have their own personal decisions to make, but it stops when it impacts other people,"" Wicks said. ""When we add the COVID-19 vaccine legislatively, as you mentioned — measles, mumps, other vaccines are already on [...]","Frank Buckley talks with California Assemblymember Buffy Wicks on vaccine mandates and how people may abuse personal exemptions. ""Yes, people have their own personal decisions to make, but it stops when it impacts other people,"" Wicks said. ""When we add the COVID-19 vaccine legislatively, as you mentioned — measles, mumps, other vaccines are already on that list — that loophole will not be able to be abused.""",2021-10-24 21:08:25,"Frank Buckley talks with California Assemblymember Buffy Wicks on vaccine mandates and how people may abuse personal exemptions. “Yes, people have their own personal decisions to make, but it stops when it impacts other people,” Wicks said. “When we add the COVID-19 vaccine legislatively, as you mentioned — measles, mumps, other vaccines are already on that list — that loophole will not be able to be abused.” Submit",,ktla,True,"[('Frank Buckley', 'PERSON'), ('California Assemblymember Buffy Wicks', 'ORG'), ('COVID-19', 'ORG')]"
Jeff Bezos Unveils Plans for Future Blue Origin Commercial Space Station,https://hypebeast.com/2021/10/jeff-bezos-unveils-plans-for-future-blue-origin-commercial-space-station,['Tech'],,,"Jeff Bezos has officially announced plans for his space venture Blue Origin to build its own commercial space station called the Orbital Reef.The Orbital Reef is set to begin operation in the second half of this decade and will be home to researchers, industrial and commercial customers and international visitors. Orbital Reef is a project in partnership with Sierra Space. Sierra Space has worked on multiple projects include the Dream Chaser, a spacecraft designed to carry cargo, hopefully, one day, humans, to the International Space Station. The Dream Chaser is scheduled for its first cargo flight in 2022.Orbital Reef is expected to host 10 people in separate living quarters and will be a place where researchers can conduct research. Blue Origin describes Orbital Reef as a ""mixed-use business park"" that will feature various vessels for a diverse range of amenities and utilities. With an open system architecture, Orbital Reef will be able to allow those from media and travel companies, investors and other space agencies to comfortably visit the space.In a statement Blue Origin said, ""The station will open the next chapter of human space exploration and development by facilitating the growth of a vibrant ecosystem and business model for the future.""In other tech news, NASA is launching a major uncrewed Moon mission in February 2022.Click here to view full gallery at HYPEBEAST","Jeff Bezos has officially announced plans for his space venture Blue Origin to build its own commercial space station called the Orbital Reef.The Orbital Reef is set to begin operation in the second half of this decade and will be home to researchers, industrial and commercial customers and international visitors. Orbital Reef is a project in partnership with Sierra Space. Sierra Space has worked on multiple projects include the Dream Chaser, a spacecraft designed to carry cargo, hopefully, one day, humans, to the International Space Station. The Dream Chaser is scheduled for its first cargo flight in 2022.Orbital Reef is expected to host 10 people in separate living quarters and will be a place where researchers can conduct research. Blue Origin describes Orbital Reef as a ""mixed-use business park"" that will feature various vessels for a diverse range of amenities and utilities. With an open system architecture, Orbital Reef will be able to allow those from media and travel companies, investors and other space agencies to comfortably visit the space.In a statement Blue Origin said, ""The station will open the next chapter of human space exploration and development by facilitating the growth of a vibrant ecosystem and business model for the future.""In other tech news, NASA is launching a major uncrewed Moon mission in February 2022.Click here to view full gallery at HYPEBEAST",2021-10-26 08:53:50,"Jeff Bezos has officially announced plans for his space venture Blue Origin to build its own commercial space station called the Orbital Reef. The Orbital Reef is set to begin operation in the second half of this decade and will be home to researchers, industrial and commercial customers and international visitors. Orbital Reef is a project in partnership with Sierra Space. Sierra Space has worked on multiple projects include the Dream Chaser, a spacecraft designed to carry cargo, hopefully, one day, humans, to the International Space Station . The Dream Chaser is scheduled for its first cargo flight in 2022. Orbital Reef is expected to host 10 people in separate living quarters and will be a place where researchers can conduct research. Blue Origin describes Orbital Reef as a “mixed-use business park” that will feature various vessels for a diverse range of amenities and utilities. With an open system architecture, Orbital Reef will be able to allow those from media and travel companies, investors and other space agencies to comfortably visit the space. In a statement Blue Origin said, “The station will open the next chapter of human space exploration and development by facilitating the growth of a vibrant ecosystem and business model for the future.” In other tech news, NASA is launching a major uncrewed Moon mission in February 2022 .",,hypebeast,True,"[('Jeff Bezos', 'PERSON'), ('Blue Origin', 'ORG'), ('the Orbital Reef', 'LAW'), ('The Orbital Reef', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the second half of this decade', 'DATE'), ('Orbital Reef', 'PERSON'), ('Sierra Space', 'ORG'), ('Sierra Space', 'PERSON'), ('the Dream Chaser', 'ORG'), ('one day', 'DATE'), ('the International Space Station', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('2022.Orbital', 'CARDINAL'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('Blue Origin', 'ORG'), ('Orbital Reef', 'PERSON'), ('Orbital Reef', 'PERSON'), ('Blue Origin', 'ORG'), ('NASA', 'ORG'), ('Moon', 'PERSON'), ('February 2022.Click', 'DATE'), ('HYPEBEAST', 'ORG')]"
India’s Chalo acquires Amazon-backed bus aggregator Shuttl,https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/chalo-acquires-amazon-backed-bus-aggregator-shuttl/,"['Asia', 'Fundings & Exits', 'Transportation', 'Amazon', 'Chalo', 'india', 'Shuttl']",['Manish Singh'],,"Chalo, a startup that is digitizing bus commutes in India and which recently raised $40 million in a financing round, has acquired Amazon-backed app-based office commute bus aggregator Shuttl in an all-cash deal, the two said on Tuesday. Chalo founder and chief executive Mohit Dubey said the acquisition of Shuttl, which operates thousands of buses […]","Chalo, a startup that is digitizing bus commutes in India and which recently raised $40 million in a financing round, has acquired Amazon-backed app-based office commute bus aggregator Shuttl in an all-cash deal, the two said on Tuesday. Chalo founder and chief executive Mohit Dubey said the acquisition of Shuttl, which operates thousands of buses aimed at working professionals, will help his startup gain presence in many parts of the country including metro cities, broaden the technology and product offerings, and also supercharge the the firm’s overseas expansion efforts. “Shuttl and Chalo, these are the firms that are positioned to become the largest mobility firms in the world. I wish the pandemic had not happened, but it has allowed the two companies with a similar focus to come together,” he said in an interview with TechCrunch. Dubey declined to disclose the financial terms of the deal, but said Shuttl co-founder and chief executive Amit Singh has agreed to continue his journey. Chalo will continue to use Shuttl’s branding, he said. “We started out to take the pain away from daily commuters. In the process we ended up building a category, and inspiring others from different parts of the world to do the same. It’s a bittersweet moment for us. We believe the team and legacy of Shuttl will thrive equally well in the new set-up,” said Singh in a statement. For investors of Shuttl, too, it’s a bittersweet moment. The startup had been struggling to raise a new financing round and had cut its workforce to address the pandemic. For months, murmurs around Shuttl shutting shops were floating. Shuttl had raised over $97 million in a series of financing rounds, according to data intelligence platform Tracxn. The startup counts Amazon, Times Internet, Sequoia Capital India, Lightspeed Venture Partners, and Toyota among its backers. Chalo said that the entire current team of Shuttl, including several key executives who have been part of the startup from the beginning, will continue in their roles. Dubey said he has been engaging with Shuttl’s Singh for several years, but the two began acquisition talks only two months ago. This is a developing story. More to follow…",2021-10-26 08:15:24,,,techcrunch,True,"[('India', 'GPE'), ('$40 million', 'MONEY'), ('Amazon', 'ORG'), ('Shuttl', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('Mohit Dubey', 'PERSON'), ('Shuttl', 'ORG'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('metro', 'FAC'), ('Shuttl and Chalo', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('TechCrunch', 'ORG'), ('Dubey', 'PERSON'), ('Shuttl', 'PERSON'), ('Amit Singh', 'PERSON'), ('Chalo', 'ORG'), ('Shuttl', 'ORG'), ('daily', 'DATE'), ('Shuttl', 'ORG'), ('Singh', 'GPE'), ('Shuttl', 'GPE'), ('months', 'DATE'), ('Shuttl', 'ORG'), ('Shuttl', 'ORG'), ('over $97 million', 'MONEY'), ('Tracxn', 'NORP'), ('Amazon', 'ORG'), ('Times', 'ORG'), ('Sequoia Capital India', 'ORG'), ('Lightspeed Venture Partners', 'ORG'), ('Toyota', 'ORG'), ('Chalo', 'PERSON'), ('Shuttl', 'ORG'), ('Dubey', 'PERSON'), ('Shuttl’s Singh', 'PERSON'), ('several years', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('only two months ago', 'DATE')]"
World Fund is a new €350M climate VC fund incubated by Green search engine Ecosia,https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/world-fund-is-a-new-e350m-climate-vc-fund-incubated-by-green-search-engine-ecosia/,"['Europe', 'TC']",['Mike Butcher'],,"You might have previously thought that Ecosia was a nice-to-have search engine that planted trees when you punched-in a search term. Lovely. How nice. But no. Ecosia’s founders and the network around it are far more serious about climate change than that superficial assessment might suggest. Last year in March 2020, just before the world […]","You might have previously thought that Ecosia was a nice-to-have search engine that planted trees when you punched-in a search term. Lovely. How nice. But no. Ecosia’s founders and the network around it are far more serious about climate change than that superficial assessment might suggest. Last year in March 2020, just before the world started to close down amid the Pandemic, that network got together and decided enough was enough: a new VC fund was needed to tackle the Climate Crisis in a different way. So today, World Fund, a new Climate Tech VC is launching with a €350 million fund targeting startups building technology that can help decarbonize the planet. World Fund claims its Europe’s largest dedicated climate tech VC. How did they build that size of a fund that fast? Well, it contains over 60 investors including current and former European tech founders, but also very few institutional LPs, hence why it could raise in such a relatively short time. Incubated by Ecosia, the fund will focus on energy, transport, food and agriculture, manufacturing, and buildings. As we’ve seen, the built environment is a huge contributor to CO2. Cities consume over two-thirds of the world’s energy and account for more than 70% of global CO2 emissions. World Fund’s says its mission will be to save 2 gigatons of emissions by 2040 – the equivalent to 4% of all global emissions. This is pretty good for one single firm, although the scale of the issue is enormous, with the world’s emissions needing to be laved by 2030 for the planet to have a chance of escaping 1.5 degrees warming. Key to this is using what it calls the Climate Performance Potential (CPP) as a key leading indicator for funding. Each company World Fund backs will need to be able to demonstrate it has the potential to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by at least 100 megatonnes CO2e every year, said the firm, as “only companies enabling a decarbonized world can become the most valuable companies of the next decade.” Danijel Višević, General partner, World Fund said: “Europe urgently needs to stop continuing business as usual, relying on the continued use of fossil fuels. This continent has the research, innovation, and political awareness to lead the world in the fight against climate change. However, until now, there hasn’t been the venture support to ensure these solutions go from idea to success. This is why we’re launching the World Fund, to be the ultimate partner to back the tech entrepreneurs of Europe that will create the most valuable companies of the next decade while tackling the climate crisis.” Doubling down on Europe as a place to make climate tech investors would seem to make sense. 50% more climate tech patents have come from Europe than the US and China between 2019 and 2020, But only €6bn of VC funding went into European companies up to 2013 compared to €25bn and €17bn invested in the US and China respectively. Plus, according to World Fund’s research, there are 41 funds in North America with more than $100 million assets under management, compared to only six in Europe, and the majority of specific European climate tech VC funds have less than $40m to back disruptive technology. Furthermore, World Fund says there were more climate tech companies founded in Europe (102) between 2019 and 2021, than the US and China combined (80). Meanwhile, the European Commission’s Horizon 2020 fund is contributing €33bn to climate-relevant R&D. Making up the fund will be Tim Schumacher, co-founder of domain marketplace Sedo (and investor in Ecosia, Zolar, gridX, Pachama and CarbonCloud); Danijel Visevic, a former journalist who covered climate tech, startups and venture capital; Daria Saharova, worked at SevenVentures and Holtzbrinck. The team also also includes Craig Douglas, formerly with SET Ventures; and Christian Kroll as a venture partner, the founder and CEO of Ecosia. World Fund has revealed that it has invested in three companies so far: a meat-replacement startup, one in waste reduction, and Qoa Company. Which replaces Cocoa, a large source of CO2 emissions in agriculture. Global ‘competitors’ to World Fund include Astanor, Pale Blue Dot and 2150 VC which this month raised a $312m fund. The investment team also includes experts such as mechanical and chemical engineers, physicists, and a mathematician. LPs include Trivago co-founder Rolf Schrömgens; Econos, a sustainable investment platform founded by Alexander Samwer; serial female entrepreneur and author Verena Pausder and her husband Philipp Pausder, the founder of Thermondo. In addition, a leading scientific and advisory board including Max Planck Institute of Innovation & Entrepreneurship Professor director Dietmar Harhoff (who is also advising the German government and is a recipient of the Bundesverdienstkreuz – Order of Merit of the Federal Republic of Germany); academic director and Scientists for Future founder Dr Gregor Hagedorn; and Deputy Head of Responsible Research at Fraunhofer Institute Simone Kaiser help advise World Fund. Tim Schumacher, General Partner at World Fund, added: “I’ve been investing in technology for over ten years now, both in regular software and in climate tech, and during that time my climate investments outperformed my other investments. Undoubtedly, one of the reasons for this is the caliber of people attracted to working on the largest problem humanity faces. At World Fund, we recognize that to tackle climate change, investing in new technology needs to be profitable and scalable.” Daria Saharova, General Partner at World Fund, said: “There’s a huge opportunity to back the startups helping to roll back the clock on the climate crisis and transform the way whole sectors operate. From farming startups to battery technology, startups addressing climate change need more funds with deep pockets and a commitment to support dynamic companies, to ensure they can fulfill their potential.”",2021-10-26 07:01:30,,,techcrunch,True,"[('Ecosia', 'ORG'), ('Ecosia', 'ORG'), ('Last year', 'DATE'), ('March 2020', 'DATE'), ('VC', 'ORG'), ('the Climate Crisis', 'ORG'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('VC', 'PRODUCT'), ('€350 million', 'MONEY'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('VC', 'PRODUCT'), ('60', 'CARDINAL'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('Ecosia', 'ORG'), ('two-thirds', 'CARDINAL'), ('more than 70%', 'PERCENT'), ('World Fund’s', 'ORG'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('2040', 'DATE'), ('4%', 'PERCENT'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('2030', 'DATE'), ('1.5 degrees', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Climate Performance Potential', 'ORG'), ('CPP', 'ORG'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('at least 100', 'CARDINAL'), ('every year', 'DATE'), ('the next decade', 'DATE'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('the World Fund', 'ORG'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('the next decade', 'DATE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('50%', 'PERCENT'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('between 2019 and 2020', 'DATE'), ('only €6bn', 'MONEY'), ('VC', 'ORG'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('2013', 'DATE'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('World Fund’s', 'ORG'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('North America', 'LOC'), ('more than $100 million', 'MONEY'), ('only six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('VC', 'ORG'), ('less than $40', 'MONEY'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('102', 'CARDINAL'), ('between 2019 and 2021', 'DATE'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('80', 'CARDINAL'), ('the European Commission’s', 'ORG'), ('Horizon 2020', 'EVENT'), ('Tim Schumacher', 'PERSON'), ('Sedo', 'PERSON'), ('Ecosia', 'GPE'), ('Zolar', 'GPE'), ('Pachama', 'PERSON'), ('CarbonCloud', 'ORG'), ('Danijel Visevic', 'PERSON'), ('Daria Saharova', 'ORG'), ('SevenVentures and Holtzbrinck', 'ORG'), ('Craig Douglas', 'PERSON'), ('SET Ventures', 'ORG'), ('Christian Kroll', 'PERSON'), ('Ecosia', 'ORG'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Qoa Company', 'PERSON'), ('CO2', 'PRODUCT'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('Astanor', 'PERSON'), ('Pale Blue Dot', 'PERSON'), ('2150', 'CARDINAL'), ('VC', 'ORG'), ('this month', 'DATE'), ('312', 'MONEY'), ('LPs', 'CARDINAL'), ('Trivago co-founder', 'ORG'), ('Rolf Schrömgens', 'PERSON'), ('Econos', 'PRODUCT'), ('Alexander Samwer', 'PERSON'), ('Verena Pausder', 'PERSON'), ('Philipp Pausder', 'PERSON'), ('Thermondo', 'ORG'), ('Max Planck Institute of Innovation & Entrepreneurship', 'ORG'), ('Dietmar Harhoff', 'PERSON'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('the Federal Republic of Germany', 'GPE'), ('Gregor Hagedorn', 'PERSON'), ('Deputy Head of', 'PERSON'), ('Fraunhofer Institute Simone Kaiser', 'ORG'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('Tim Schumacher', 'PERSON'), ('General Partner', 'ORG'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('ten years', 'DATE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('World Fund', 'ORG'), ('Daria Saharova', 'PERSON'), ('General Partner', 'ORG'), ('World Fund', 'ORG')]"
"Marcy Venture Partners, cofounded by Jay-Z, just closed its second fund with $325 million",https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/marcy-venture-partners-cofounded-by-jay-z-just-closed-its-second-fund-with-325-million/,"['TC', 'Venture Capital', 'Jay Brown', 'Jay Z', 'Larry Marcus', 'Marcy Venture Partners', 'Savage X Fenty', 'Simulate', 'stockx', 'Therabody', 'venture capital']",['Connie Loizos'],,"Marcy Venture Partners, the venture firm cofounded in 2018 by Shawn Carter (Jay-Z), former Roc Nation CEO Jay Brown, and former Walden VC general partner Larry Marcus, says it has closed its second fund with $325 million in capital commitments. The team, which closed its debut fund with $85 million, is now managing $600 million […]","Marcy Venture Partners, the venture firm cofounded in 2018 by Shawn Carter (Jay-Z), former Roc Nation CEO Jay Brown, and former Walden VC general partner Larry Marcus, says it has closed its second fund with $325 million in capital commitments. The team, which closed its debut fund with $85 million, is now managing $600 million in assets altogether, says cofounder Marcus. The firm describes itself as having a “consumer, culture and positive impact” investment strategy, and it says the majority of its existing portfolio companies are founded or run by people who identify as women or people of color. To date, the trio has written checks to at least 21 companies, including in fashion, skin care, and food companies. Among those many bets includes Rihanna’s lingerie company Savage X Fenty; the sneaker marketplace StockX; Therabody, which makes percussion therapy tools; Simulate, which makes plant-based, chicken-flavored nuggets; and an allergen-free cookie maker called Partake Foods. Carter and company have also begun investing in crypto projects, supporting Bitski, a San Francisco-based startup NFT marketplace, earlier this year, and investing more recently in spatial LABS (sLABS), a tech incubator that focuses on the metaverse and blockchain-based products. The San Francisco- and L.A.-based firm, named after the Marcy Projects in Brooklyn where Carter grew up, was initially targeting $200 million for the newest fund, per an SEC filing from April.",2021-10-26 04:35:51,,,techcrunch,True,"[('Marcy Venture Partners', 'ORG'), ('2018', 'DATE'), ('Shawn Carter', 'PERSON'), ('Jay-Z', 'ORG'), ('Roc Nation', 'ORG'), ('Jay Brown', 'PERSON'), ('Walden VC', 'ORG'), ('Larry Marcus', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('$325 million', 'MONEY'), ('$85 million', 'MONEY'), ('$600 million', 'MONEY'), ('Marcus', 'ORG'), ('at least 21', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rihanna', 'GPE'), ('Savage X Fenty', 'ORG'), ('Therabody', 'PERSON'), ('Simulate', 'ORG'), ('Partake Foods', 'ORG'), ('Carter', 'PERSON'), ('Bitski', 'PERSON'), ('San Francisco', 'GPE'), ('NFT', 'ORG'), ('earlier this year', 'DATE'), ('The San Francisco-', 'GPE'), ('the Marcy Projects', 'ORG'), ('Brooklyn', 'GPE'), ('Carter', 'PERSON'), ('$200 million', 'MONEY'), ('SEC', 'ORG'), ('April', 'DATE')]"
